Kyle Romero

 ♀ Jersey City, NJ (NYC Metro Area)
 ⋈ kgromero@gmail.com
 □ (281) 857-9006
 □ in/kyleromero
 ⋈ kgromero.com

SUMMARY

Software Engineering Leader with 10 years as a full-stack developer and 7 years in management, living in the NYC Metro Area. Looking for the next opportunity to lead a development organization to success, maximize business value, and provide great user experiences.

EXPERIENCE

Director of Software Development

Raymour & Flanigan (Retail)

March 2023 - May 2024, Jersey City, NJ (remote)

- Initiatives: ERP Migration to NetSuite, WMS Migration to Korber, Omnichannel Sales Experience via E-Commerce Site, 3rd Party API Integrations (ChargeAfter, Bringg).
- Org. Size: 3 Managers (AppDev Team, Oracle Team, Data Integrations / API Team), 4 Architects, 30 Developers (mix of internal and near/off shore resources).
- Primary Tech Stack: React, .NET (C#, UWP, ASP.NET Core), SQL Server, Oracle DB, Azure, AWS, Windows Server, Git (Azure DevOps), Boomi, Snowflake.
- Defined and executed organizational strategy (1 and 5 year) processes (Agile, DevOps) and coding/review standards.
- · Directly led change control and release management processes, leading to 50% decrease in production defect rate.
- Introduced Microsoft CoPilot and ChatGPT AI into development process, leading to significant increase in developer output.
- Aligned cross-functional teams within matrix IT organization and coordinated with infrastructure, product management, business intelligence, design, and ecommerce organizations.
- Negotiated, reviewed, and managed development partner (near-shore / on-shore) and vendor contracts and resources, which resulted in reduction of contract costs by 40%.
- Forecasted and controlled organizational budget and credit card, reducing YoY costs by 25%.
- Operated as SME alongside architects (direct reports) to define and execute software architecture strategy and ensure 24/7 on-call support was available.

Director of Software Development

MEARS Group (Energy)

October 2017 - March 2023, Jersey City, NJ (remote)

- **Projects:** Mission Critical SOX-compliant and high-availability internally developed Revenue/Time/Equipment Field Capture solution, used by over 700 field construction crews across the US and which sped up the closing process by 75%. Electron based Field Safety Capture application with online/offline capability that digitized all safety documentation field crews must capture.
- Team Size: 4 Developers, 1 PM, 7 Offshore (100% remote team).
- Primary Tech Stack: .NET (C#, ASP.NET Core), SQL Server, Sqlite3, Azure / Windows Server, JavaScript (Angular / React / Node / Electron), Git, PowerBI, PowerAutomate. Java (Spring Boot).
- Titles: Manager (2017 2020), Senior Manager (2020 2021), Director (2021 2023).
- · Reported directly to CIO and tasked with digital transformation and continuous improvement, including participating in Six Sigma and Kaizen initiatives.
- Traveled to various U.S. locations to roll out applications and lead Change Management (25% travel).
- · Implemented and trained organization on DevOps/CICD, Agile Scrum, Kanban, GitFlow, and QA processes, which increased delivery speed by 50%.
- Onboarded and coordinated offshore development partner based out of India.
- Nominated to Innovator Group and Quanta Leadership Academy 2.

Team Lead

Worldwide Machinery (Construction)

April 2016 - October 2017, Houston, TX

- · Led internal software development team (3 internal and 5 contract developers) and reported to co-owner of company.
- Full-stack development using .NET, MS-SQL, and React which delivered mission-critical asset management software (desktop, mobile, and web) that managed \$300mil worth of heavy machinery assets.
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Built mobile-first SPA to enable employees to utilize real-time telemetry on machinery assets.}$

Technical Lead

HP Inc. (Consumer Electronics)

December 2011 - February 2016, Houston, TX

- $\bullet \ \ \text{Designated as technical lead over mission-critical third level support tool with 10k+ global users.}$
- Full-stack development delivering 3-tier web applications using .NET, MS SQL, and JavaScript.
- Gained exposure to big data (Hadoop / HP Vertica) and BI/analytics (PowerBI / Tableau).
- Led logical split and cloning of system during HP's split into HPE and HP Inc..
- Titles: Senior Developer (2011 2013), Technical Lead (2013 2016).

Software Developer

X-Fab Texas (Semiconductors)

August 2007 - December 2011, Lubbock, TX

- Full-Stack developer specializing in .NET, MS SQL, C++, and Perl development (Windows and Linux).
- Built responsive 3-tier web applications (utilizing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript) and introduced Subversion source control to company.
- · Deployed over 50 plasma trace machine monitoring Perle Modules that integrated with custom built monitoring and reporting software.
- Deployed distributed databases and web applications in the U.S., Germany, and Malaysia.
- Interned as developer the summer before being hired full time.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

Texas Tech University • Lubbock, TX • 2005 - 2009

• Covered Computer Science and Electrical Engineering Topics

SKILLS

- **General:** People Management, Project Management, Financial Management, System Architecture, Full-Stack Development, Entire SDLC, Continuous Improvement, Legacy Systems
- Processes: DevOps, CICD, Agile Scrum, Kanban, GitFlow, Matrix Organization
- Architectures: N-Tier, REST API, PWA, SPA, SSR, Serverless, MVC, Event Driven, Offline-First, Distributed, Microservices, Containerized/Orchestrated
- .NET: C#, VB.NET, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, UWP, SignalR, Webforms
- JavaScript: Node, NPM, React, Electron, Angular, TypeScript, SvelteKit
- Scripting: Python
- Web: HTML, CSS, Tailwind, Bootstrap
- Containerization: Docker, K8s
- DB: SQL Server, Sqlite3, Oracle
- Cloud: Azure, AWS, Netlify, DigitalOcean, Fly.io
- Servers: Windows Server, Linux (Ubuntu/Debian)
- $\bullet \ \, \textbf{Tooling:} \ \, \textbf{Azure DevOps, GitHub, Bitbucket, Visual Studio/VS Code, SSMS, DBeaver, Jira} \\$
- ETL: Boomi, SSIS
- Message Queue: Azure Service Bus
- Al: ChatGPT, Microsoft CoPilot, Claude, Cursor
- Data Warehouse: Snowflake
- Reporting: SSRS, PowerBI
- Other: Java Spring, Sharepoint Online, PowerApps, PowerAutomate, Twilio, JWT, Swagger, C++, Raspberry Pi